<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>XdHacks-Mini on Victor Zheng</title>
    <link>https://victorzheng.ca/categories/xdhacks-mini/</link>
    <description>Recent content in XdHacks-Mini on Victor Zheng</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://victorzheng.ca/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:18:53 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://victorzheng.ca/categories/xdhacks-mini/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Organizing Climate Code 2021</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/technology/organizing-climate-code-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:18:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/technology/organizing-climate-code-2021/</guid>
      <description>In 2020, I joined Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s leading high-school hackathon organization, XdHacks Mini Vancouver.
I worked on and developed the biggest high-school hackathon event ever, and fundraised over $1,000 for the event.
Looking back, this was one of the best experiences of my life as I learned a lot about how to organize events, how to lead a team, and how to work with others. Running this hackathon showed me a lot about managing people, how people work, and how to be a leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Started Hack Team 6</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/technology/why-we-started-hack-team-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:18:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/technology/why-we-started-hack-team-6/</guid>
      <description>You may have noticed the lack of hackathons from our global rounds this past year. And you’d be right. We’ve been working hard on a new program called Hack Team 6. The mission? – train high-school students&amp;rsquo; event planning skills online, efficiently, and in a manner that is fun.
Joining XdHacks Mini in 2020, the landscape was different than today. XdHacks Mini was the only high-school hackathon organization in British Columbia (where I’m from), Zoom was still relatively new, and people were still comfortable with online events and online hackathons.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
