<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Victor Zheng</title>
    <link>https://victorzheng.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Victor Zheng</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://victorzheng.ca/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 15:18:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://victorzheng.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Blogs</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/robotics-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 15:18:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/robotics-blogs/</guid>
      <description>From 2018 to 2021, I was part of a robotics team which I had the chance of writing blogs about</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing Climate Code 2021</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/organizing-climate-code-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:18:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/organizing-climate-code-2021/</guid>
      <description>In 2020, I joined Vancouver&amp;rsquo;s leading high-school hackathon organization, XdHacks Mini Vancouver.
I worked on and developed the biggest high-school hackathon event ever, and fundraised over $1,000 for the event.
Looking back, this was one of the best experiences of my life as I learned a lot about how to organize events, how to lead a team, and how to work with others. Running this hackathon showed me a lot about managing people, how people work, and how to be a leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hart House Feature on the Chess Club</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/feature-on-chess-club-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:19:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/feature-on-chess-club-women/</guid>
      <description>The following page was written by Megan Mueller at Hart House. Hart House houses the Hart House Chess Club, the official chess club of the University of Toronto since 1895. This year, I am proud to serve as it&amp;rsquo;s President/Secretary.
The original post is accessible here: https://harthouse.ca/blog/the-ascent-of-the-female-chess-player-hart-house-club-provides-welcoming-environment
Women&amp;rsquo;s Chess is strong at UofT as of 2023 Female students are advancing in the game of chess, a realm traditionally held by men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globe and Mail Feature on the Hart House Chess Club</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/feature-on-the-chess-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 12:32:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/feature-on-the-chess-club/</guid>
      <description>The following page was written by Cecil Rosner, one of the only chess columnists currently still writing articles as of 2023. Rosner&amp;rsquo;s pieces are published weekly on The Globe and Mail here.
I was featured by Rosner in a piece titled &amp;ldquo;Canada’s biggest college chess club still going strong after 127 years &amp;ldquo; on Janruary 8, 2023. I did the interview with Bowen Zhang, at that time the Fundraising Director for the Hart House Chess Club.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Canadian University Tennis Club Championship</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/the-first-canadian-championship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 17:42:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/the-first-canadian-championship/</guid>
      <description>On February 26th, the cumulation of over a year of planning resulted in the first ever Canadian University Tennis Club Championship at the University of Waterloo. This is my report from organizing and directing the event.
Firstly, for context, I am the President of the University of Toronto Tennis Club, a Club with 145 paid members and an overall impact of ~800 students annually. This was one of my dreams ever since joining the Club and I&amp;rsquo;m really happy to be writing this post on the successful event that it was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Skipped Grade 12</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/why-i-skipped-grade-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:20:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/why-i-skipped-grade-12/</guid>
      <description>Over two years ago, back in 2020, I decided to &amp;ldquo;skip&amp;rdquo; grade 12. Here were the reasons that I listed back then (Mar. 2021), unchanged from the moment I wrote them.
The Reasons You get an extra year of your life working or learning compared to a regular student. Benefits your wealth, your experiences, etc. COVID should be gone by fall, but who knows what will happen next year? You boost your morale because it seems like you accomplished something great or made yourself special You don&amp;rsquo;t have to go to prom, grad photo-ops with some people you hardly know Universities may like your application more since you graduated early.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2023 Reading Week Open</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/the-2023-reading-week-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 17:56:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/the-2023-reading-week-open/</guid>
      <description>I had the honour of writing the Event Report for the 2023 Hart House Reading Week Open Chess Tournament during Family Day Long Weekend 2023. As the lead organizer of the event, it was a great to see such an exciting event take place and for us to pull off an excellent quality event. The report I wrote with all images can be found here: https://harthousechess.com/2023/02/24/nikolay-noritsyn-wins-in-strong-crown-section-at-2023-reading-week-open/.
Please see below for the text (no images) that I wrote for the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UofT Makes a Splash at the 2023 PanAmerican Intercollegiate Chess Tournament</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/panam-chess-tournament/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 13:03:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/panam-chess-tournament/</guid>
      <description>I was honoured earlier this year to have the opportunity to attend and write the official event report from the Hart House Chess Club&amp;rsquo;s PanAmerican Intercollegiate Chess Tournament in Seattle, Washington. As a player in the tournament and the lead organizer for the team&amp;rsquo;s trip, it was as no-brainer for me to also write the event report. The report can be accessed here: https://harthousechess.com/2023/01/22/uoft-makes-a-splash-at-the-2023-panamerican-intercollegiate-chess-championship/.
From January 5th – 9th, 2023, eight UofT students travelled over 3316 kilometers to Seattle, Washington, USA, for the annual Pan American Intercollegiate Chess Championship, the pinnacle of international collegiate chess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrabble Course Project Csc207</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/scrabble-course-project-csc207/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:21:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/scrabble-course-project-csc207/</guid>
      <description>In 2022, my team created a re-write of Scrabble. For all the details, visit our team site here: https://github.com/CSC207-2022F-UofT/course-project-scrabble.
Overall, the project was very exciting and my team had a lot of fun. I&amp;rsquo;ve attached our Readme.md below in case we missed it. Alongside the PDF explaining our software design. I was mainly responsible for the UI design.
PDF of software design: download the pdf here
Scrabble Welcome to Scrabble, a game played and loved by millions around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Holidays Open Chess Tournament</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/2022-holidays-open-chess-tournament/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 20:49:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/2022-holidays-open-chess-tournament/</guid>
      <description>The Hart House Holidays Open hosted by the historic Hart House Chess Club (HHCC) returned for the first time since the pandemic. This holiday season tradition had been sidelined since Dec. 2019 thanks to the COVID-19 pandemic and the gathering restrictions stemmed from it. I had the privilege (or responsibility as a HHCC Exec) of joining the tournament organizing team as one of the lead organizers for the event.
The Event Recap 212 participants descended on the Great Hall of Hart House at the University of Toronto from Dec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing the Fall 2022 UofT Tennis Club vs Skule Tennis Club Match</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/uttc-vs-stc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 23:14:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/uttc-vs-stc/</guid>
      <description>On October 24, 2022, I organized the Fall 2022 Skule Tennis Club (STC) vs UofT Tennis Club (UTTC) match, which resulted in a resounding victory for UTTC 11-5. Going in to the match, I had worked with Sara, STC&amp;rsquo;s President to make sure that we had everything ready to go and people to play against. I also worked with Sir Winston Churchill Park Tennis Club by booking the courts for a very low cost of $10 per member for 4 hours from 3pm-7pm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 UofT Tennis Club Championship</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/2022-uoft-tennis-club-championship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 20:50:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/2022-uoft-tennis-club-championship/</guid>
      <description>I organized and ran a successful Club Championship with 54 players!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Varsity Feature for the UofT Tennis Club</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/varsity-feature-uoft-tennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 20:59:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/varsity-feature-uoft-tennis/</guid>
      <description>A feature on the UofT Tennis Club from The Varsity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Started Hack Team 6</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/why-we-started-hack-team-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:18:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/why-we-started-hack-team-6/</guid>
      <description>You may have noticed the lack of hackathons from our global rounds this past year. And you’d be right. We’ve been working hard on a new program called Hack Team 6. The mission? – train high-school students&amp;rsquo; event planning skills online, efficiently, and in a manner that is fun.
Joining XdHacks Mini in 2020, the landscape was different than today. XdHacks Mini was the only high-school hackathon organization in British Columbia (where I’m from), Zoom was still relatively new, and people were still comfortable with online events and online hackathons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Garry Kasparov at Collision 2022</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/meeting-garry-kasparov-at-collision-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:14:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/meeting-garry-kasparov-at-collision-2022/</guid>
      <description>On the morning of June 21st, 2022, I woke up to a text message to our Club&amp;rsquo;s account from a random stranger. It said something along the lines of how they needed chess sets for an important chess event happening in Downtown Toronto that afternoon, and that we were one of the only Clubs in Toronto that they thought would be able to help. I quickly responded by saying that we&amp;rsquo;re not open and that we don&amp;rsquo;t usually offer chess equipment for such a last minute request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running a Hackathon at the International Science and Engineering Fair</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/running-a-mini-hackathon-isef/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:14:44 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/posts/running-a-mini-hackathon-isef/</guid>
      <description>The International Science and Engineer Fair is one of the most famous science fairs in the world, where over 1500+ students come together to showcase their research and innovative skills and compete for over $6,000,000 in prizes. XdHacks Mini was invited to organize a mini-hackathon for this event, in-person, in Atlanta, Georgia. This is my experience.
0. It all first started when Kaden, our President got an email from the Society for Science about hosting a hackathon at ISEF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://victorzheng.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://victorzheng.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>about</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
